Guide to the Stanford University, Office of the General Counsel, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of the General Counsel, records
1897-2013
SC1003
Stanford University. Office of the General Counsel.
59.5 Linear feet (40 boxes)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were transferred from the Office of the General Counsel, 2000.
Information about Access
The materials are restricted.
Biographical/Historical note
The Office of the General Counsel (OGC) is responsible for addressing all of the legal issues arising out of the activities of Stanford University, Stanford Hospital and Clinics and Lucile Salter Packard Children's Hospital at Stanford.
Scope and Contents note
Records from the legal office pertain to real estate matters, including the Stanford Shopping Center, other leases, and gift deeds.
Access Terms
Stanford University--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Property records, 1930-1994; Accession ARCH-2000-169
  - Stanford Shopping Center original documents
    - 2A-74, and 371 (Box 1)
    - #79-149 (Box 2)
    - #151-194 (Box 3)
    - #198-305 (Box 4)
    - mixed numbers (Box 5-8)
  - Other leases numbers
    - 937- (Box 9)
    - 1011- (Box 10)
    - 1053 - (Box 11)
    - 1096- (Box 12)
    - 1154- (Box 13)
    - 1248- (Box 14)
    - 1322- (Box 15)
    - 1439- (Box 16)
    - 1543- (Box 17)
    - 1602- (Box 18)
    - 1685- (Box 19)
    - 1812- (Box 20)
    - 1892- (Box 21)
    - 1927- (Box 22)
    - 1957- (Box 23)
    - 1997- (Box 24)
    - 2064- (Box 25)
  - Ground leases/gift deeds
    - #1-130 (Box 26)
    - #132-244 (Box 27)
    - #250-291 (Box 28)
    - #292-326 (Box 29)
    - #326 cont.-397 (Box 30)
    - #398-442 (Box 31)
    - #443-528 (Box 32)
    - #530-597 (Box 33)
    - #598-688 (Box 34)
    - #689-736 (Box 35)
    - #737-770 (Box 36)
    - #770 cont.-831 (Box 37)
    - #831 cont.-888 (Box 38)
    - #889-936 (Box 39)
- Materials relating to the Founding Grant, 1897-2013; Accession ARCH-2015-157
  - Address by Jane Lathrop Stanford to BOT(booklet), 1897-02-11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address by Jane Lathrop Stanford to Board of Trustees, 1899-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Address by Jane Lathrop Stanford to Board of Trustees, 1902-10-03 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Petition to Superior Court -County of Santa Clara, 1903-06-15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Address by Jane Lathrop Stanford to Board of Trustees, 1903-07-06 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Decree and Supplementary Decree, 1907-09-27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Crothers & Crothers to Dr. Tressider re founding grant, 1945-03-26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Petition & Decree Authorizing Modification of the Trusts Related to the Creation and Operation of Stanford University, 1954-03-15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Suggested Questions & Answers for Mr. John W. Gardner, 1969-01-13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Petition for a Decree Authorizing Modification of the Trusts Related to the Creation & Operation of Stanford University, 1969-12-19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memo for the Record from Office of General Secretary re Election of Trustees by Alumni, 1970-11-05 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Certified Copy of Decree Filed 7/6/1903 re FoundingGrant (loose leaf in manila envelope), 1971-04-03 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Founding Grant with Amendments, Legislation, and Court Decrees, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rules Governing Election of Trustees by Alumni (loose leaf in brown envelope), 1973-09-19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Founders & the Architects: The Design of Stanford University, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Founding Grant with Amendments, Legislation, and Court Decrees, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Petition to Increase the Number of Trustees on the Stanford BOT, 2013-06-04 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Order Granting Petition to Increase the Number of Trustees on the Stanford Board of Trustees, 2013-07-08 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - When We Were Fifty: The Story of Stanford's Golden Jubilee (booklet), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)